# **Elizabeth Thomas**

434-373-1241 | elizabeththomas33@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/cartoelizabeth/

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

My experience throughout my career has taught me to look at every project through a proactive crossfunctional lens – evaluating the big and small details and considering how they fit into the bigger picture. I am consistently and incrementally evaluating how to make processes flow more efficiently and I ensure data governance is top of mind.

# **SKILLS**

### **TOOLS**

design: PowerBI | Adobe Illustrator | Tableau

mapping: MaPublisher | ArcGIS Pro | Google Earth

agile workflow management: Visual Studio Team Services (vsts) | Jira | Office 365

client and data management: Salesforce | SharePoint | Microsoft Teams

programing languages: Dax | M code

executive reporting and presentations Dashboards | Brand formatting | Progress monitoring

### **DESIGN PRINCIPLES**

Visual storytelling | User centered design | Data visualization | Large format plotting | Print and digital design | Brand development and implementation | Typography and color theory | Editor and copy editor skills

### LEADERSHIP CAPABILITIES

Workflow management | Process redesign | User story development | Design workshop facilitation | Corporate business presentation skills | Data management and integration | Data and process governance practices | Metadata development | Software license management | Proficiency leading other with skills in: VBA, Python, API Interactions, HTML, CSS, Dashboarding, JavaScript

# **EDUCATION**

Continuing education in progress: Google UX Design Professional Certificate Current research interests: Organizational Behavior | PMP

Bootcamp: Data Analytics & Visualization | Rice University | Completion: 2022

Certificate: Infographics and Data Visualization | Parsons School of Design | Completion: 2021

Master of Arts: Cartography – Public perception of design | University of Kansas | Coursework completed: 2015 Bachelor of Arts: Geography – GIS/Cartography | Indiana University of Pennsylvania | Graduation: May 2012

# **EMPLOYMENT**

**NextEra Energy** 

Senior Business Analyst

June 2022 – Present Remote: Juno Beach, FL

- Participated in the hiring, onboarding and continual training of operations teams including GIS, IT, and Financial Services.
- Spearheaded data governance initiatives and conducted workflow process evaluations, contributing to the development of a plan for workflow, policy, and process improvements for the executive team.
- Collaborated across technology and operational teams within an Agile framework to integrate databases from on-premises servers to cloud infrastructure and into more centralized systems.
- Conducted in-depth analysis of existing datasets to identify and rectify data errors and inconsistencies, implementing workflows for continual monitoring for both executive and implementation teams.
- Leveraged PowerBI to complete regular financial reporting for both functional and executive teams.

### S&P Global Market Intelligence

Senior Managing Cartographer

March 2016 - June 2022

Hybrid remote: Charlottesville, VA

- Led a global team of cartographers and designers, fostering skill development and creative thinking about data and graphics.
- Collaborated cross-divisionally between multiple visual teams, ensuring consistency and accuracy across products through the development of workflows and stakeholder relationships.
- Conducted design workshops with internal and external stakeholders, producing compelling visual stories to illustrate complex datasets and processes.
- Acted as the client's advocate within the Agile framework, ensuring client needs were met and bridging the gap between client management software (Salesforce), client needs, and platform technologies and data.
- Worked alongside scrum teams to develop user stories for product improvements based on client needs and feedback.
- Worked in an editor capacity with news, industry, and marketing leaders to develop cohesive narratives using both text and graphics across platforms.
- Developed new brand standards and innovative graphic ideas.

#### National Park Service, Gateway National Rec. Area

Hurricane Sandy Recovery Data Visualization Specialist

Jan. 2015 - Feb. 2016

Staten Island, NY

- Primary designer on Gateway NRA General Management Plan graphics.
- Led team of seasonal interns to achieve business unit needs.
- Developed and designed products based on client's or park unit's needs.
- Designed public-facing pamphlets, presentations, and exhibit documents.

### **United States Census Bureau**

Cartographic Products Branch Intern

July 2014 - Nov. 2014

Washington, DC

- Involvement in QA/QC on maps resulting from an automated process.
- Used open-source software and data to complete various data and design problems.
- Acted as liaison between technology teams and functional teams to ensure requirements were being met.

### **National Geographic Society**

Maps Division Intern

Jan. 2014 – April 2014 Washington, DC

- Primary Cartographer on the Pacific Crest Trail National Geographic Map.
- Worked with and organized numerous large datasets to produce a cohesive set of maps and graphics.
- · Worked with a team of editors and cartographers to complete various complex projects.